<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Daily Reflections by Mario Stallone</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/</link><description>Recent content on Daily Reflections by Mario Stallone</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 10:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mariostallone.com/reflections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-06-04/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-06-04/</guid><description>[Tobit 11:5-17; Psalms 146:1-2, 6-10; Mark 12:35-37]
“While Jesus was teaching in the temple, he said, “How can the scribes say that the Messiah is the son of David? David himself, by the Holy Spirit, declared, ‘The Lord said to my Lord, “Sit at my right hand, until I put your enemies under your feet.” ’ David himself calls him Lord; so how can he be his son?” And the large crowd was listening to him with delight.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-06-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-06-02/</guid><description>[Tobit 3:1-11, 16-17; Psalms 25:2-9; Mark 12:18-27]
“For when they rise from the dead, they neither marry nor are given in marriage, but are like angels in heaven.”- Mark 12:25 (NRSV)
In today’s Gospel, we read of the Sadducees approaching Jesus asking Him about the resurrection.
They lose the story this way, which resembles the story we read in today’s first reading from Tobit. A man dies leaving his wife without children, so according to the Mosaic law, his brother would take her as his wife, and this way all the brothers, totalling 7, were married to the woman.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-06-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-06-01/</guid><description>[Tobit 2:9-14; Psalms 112:1-2, 7-9; Mark 12:13-17]
“Jesus said to them, “Give to the emperor the things that are the emperor&amp;rsquo;s, and to God the things that are God&amp;rsquo;s.” And they were utterly amazed at him.” - Mark 12:17 (NRSV)
Today’s passage is very interesting as it speaks about taxes!
The Pharisees and the Herodians were sent to Jesus so they could try and trap Him. Jesus knowing their intentions confronts them and asks them - Why put me to the test?</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-28/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-28/</guid><description>[Sirach 44:1, 9-13; Psalms 149:1-6, 9; Mark 11:11-26]
Then Peter remembered and said to him, “Rabbi, look! The fig tree that you cursed has withered.” Jesus answered them, “Have faith in God. Truly I tell you, if you say to this mountain, ‘Be taken up and thrown into the sea,’ and if you do not doubt in your heart, but believe that what you say will come to pass, it will be done for you.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-27/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-27/</guid><description>[Sirach 42:15-25; Psalms 33:2-9; Mark 10:46-52]
Then Jesus said to him, “What do you want me to do for you?” The blind man said to him, “My teacher, let me see again.” Jesus said to him, “Go; your faith has made you well.” Immediately he regained his sight and followed him on the way. - Mark 10:51-52 (NRSV)
Today’s reading talks about the healing of the blind man.
A few things that stand out to me here are that Mark when writing about this miracle knows the name of the blind beggar - Bartimaeus son of Timaeus.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-26/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-26/</guid><description>[Sirach 36:1, 4-5, 10-17; Psalms 79:8-9, 11, 13; Mark 10:32-45]
And they said to him, “Grant us to sit, one at your right hand and one at your left, in your glory.” But Jesus said to them, “You do not know what you are asking. Are you able to drink the cup that I drink, or be baptized with the baptism that I am baptized with?” They replied, “We are able.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-21/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-21/</guid><description>[Acts 25:13-21; Psalms 103:1-2, 11-12, 19-20; John 21:15-19]
“When they had finished breakfast, Jesus said to Simon Peter, “Simon son of John, do you love me more than these?” He said to him, “Yes, Lord; you know that I love you.” Jesus said to him, “Feed my lambs.” A second time he said to him, “Simon son of John, do you love me?” He said to him, “Yes, Lord; you know that I love you.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-20/</guid><description>[Acts 22:30; 23:6-11; Psalms 16:1-2, 5, 7-11; John 17:20-26]
&amp;ldquo;That night the Lord stood near him and said, “Keep up your courage! For just as you have testified for me in Jerusalem, so you must bear witness also in Rome.” - Acts 23:11 (NRSV)
In today’s First Reading, we read about Paul bearing witness to Christ in Rome.
These words in the reading stood out to me - Jesus, standing by Paul, asking him to Keep up His courage.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-19/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-19/</guid><description>[Acts 20:28-38; Psalms 68:29-30, 33-36; John 17:11-19]
“I have given them your word, and the world has hated them because they do not belong to the world, just as I do not belong to the world.” - John 17:14 (NRSV)
Jesus in today’s Gospel says that we do not belong to the world.
We - over here refers to believers of Christ, all of us! And Jesus is stating that we do not belong to the world.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-18/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-18/</guid><description>[Acts 2:44-47; Psalms 131:1-3; Luke 12:22-31]
“Consider the ravens: they neither sow nor reap, they have neither storehouse nor barn, and yet God feeds them. Of how much more value are you than the birds! And can any of you by worrying add a single hour to your span of life?
Instead, strive for his kingdom, and these things will be given to you as well.” - Luke 12:24-25, 31 (NRSV)</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-14/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-05-14/</guid><description>[Acts 18:9-18; Ps 47 2-7; John 16:20-23a]
“When a woman is in labor, she has pain, because her hour has come. But when her child is born, she no longer remembers the anguish because of the joy of having brought a human being into the world. So you have pain now; but I will see you again, and your hearts will rejoice, and no one will take your joy from you.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-26/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-26/</guid><description>[Jeremiah 20:10-13; Psalms 18:2-7; John 10:31-42]
Jesus answered, “Is it not written in your law, ‘I said, you are gods’? If those to whom the word of God came were called ‘gods’—and the scripture cannot be annulled— can you say that the one whom the Father has sanctified and sent into the world is blaspheming because I said, ‘I am God’s Son’? If I am not doing the works of my Father, then do not believe me.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-15/</guid><description>[Isaiah 65:17-21; Psalms 30:2, 4-6, 11-13; John 4:43-54]
Then he came again to Cana in Galilee where he had changed the water into wine. Now there was a royal official whose son lay ill in Capernaum. When he heard that Jesus had come from Judea to Galilee, he went and begged him to come down and heal his son, for he was at the point of death. Then Jesus said to him, “Unless you see signs and wonders you will not believe.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-10/</guid><description>[Deuteronomy 4:1, 5-9; Psalms 147:12-13, 15-16, 19-20; Matthew 5:17-19]
“Do not think that I have come to abolish the law or the prophets; I have come not to abolish but to fulfil. - Matthew 5:17 (NRSV)
In Today’s Liturgy, we read about Moses giving the Israelites a warning to heed to the law as they enter the Promised Land, and we hear Jesus tell the people that He came not to abolish the Law, but to fulfil it</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-09/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-09/</guid><description>[Daniel 3:25, 34-43; Psalms 25:4-9; Matthew 18:21-35]
Then Peter came and said to him, “Lord, if another member of the church sins against me, how often should I forgive? As many as seven times?” Jesus said to him, “Not seven times, but, I tell you, seventy-seven times. - Matthew 18:21-22 (NRSV)
In today’s Gospel we read about Jesus talking to us about forgiveness, yet again!
Peter approaches Jesus and asks him how many times must he forgive his fellow church member, As many as seven times?</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-05/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-05/</guid><description>[Genesis 37:3-4, 12-13, 17-28; Psalms 105:16-21; Matthew 21:33-43, 45-46]
They saw him from a distance, and before he came near to them, they conspired to kill him. They said to one another, “Here comes this dreamer. Come now, let us kill him and throw him into one of the pits; then we shall say that a wild animal has devoured him, and we shall see what will become of his dreams.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-04/</guid><description>[Jeremiah 17:5-10; Psalms 1:1-4, 6; Luke 16:19-31]
Thus says the Lord: Cursed are those who trust in mere mortals and make mere flesh their strength, whose hearts turn away from the Lord. They shall be like a shrub in the desert, and shall not see when relief comes. They shall live in the parched places of the wilderness, in an uninhabited salt land.
Blessed are those who trust in the Lord, whose trust is the Lord.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-02/</guid><description>[Isaiah 1:10, 16-20; Psalms 50:8-9, 16-17, 21, 23; Matthew 23:1-12]
“The scribes and the Pharisees sit on Moses' seat; therefore, do whatever they teach you and follow it; but do not do as they do, for they do not practice what they teach. - Matthew 23:2-3 (NRSV)
In today’s Gospel, we see a very interesting statement from Jesus, He tells the people to do what the Pharisees teach, but not to do as they do.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-03-01/</guid><description>[Daniel 9:4-10; Psalms 79:8-9, 11, 13; Luke 6:36-38]
Be merciful, just as your Father is merciful. “Do not judge, and you will not be judged; do not condemn, and you will not be condemned. Forgive, and you will be forgiven; give, and it will be given to you. A good measure, pressed down, shaken together, running over, will be put into your lap; for the measure you give will be the measure you get back.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-02-26/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-02-26/</guid><description>[Ezekiel 18:21-28; Psalms 130:1-8; Matthew 5:20-26]
But if the wicked turn away from all their sins that they have committed and keep all my statutes and do what is lawful and right, they shall surely live; they shall not die. None of the transgressions that they have committed shall be remembered against them; for the righteousness that they have done they shall live. Have I any pleasure in the death of the wicked, says the Lord God, and not rather that they should turn from their ways and live?</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-02-25/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-02-25/</guid><description>[Esther C:12, 14-16, 23-25; Psalms 138:1-3, 7-8; Matthew 7:7-12]
“Ask, and it will be given you; search, and you will find; knock, and the door will be opened for you. For everyone who asks receives, and everyone who searches finds, and for everyone who knocks, the door will be opened. Is there anyone among you who, if your child asks for bread, will give a stone? Or if the child asks for a fish, will give a snake?</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-02-24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-02-24/</guid><description>[Jonah 3:1-10; Jonah 3:1-10; Luke 11:29-32]
When the crowds were increasing, he began to say, “This generation is an evil generation; it asks for a sign, but no sign will be given to it except the sign of Jonah. For just as Jonah became a sign to the people of Nineveh, so the Son of Man will be to this generation. - Luke 11:29-30 (NRSV)
Today&amp;rsquo;s Liturgy focuses on Jonah and the repentance of the people of Nineveh!</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-02-23/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-02-23/</guid><description>[Isaiah 55:10-11; Psalms 34:4-7, 16-19; Matthew 6:7-15]
For if you forgive others their trespasses, your heavenly Father will also forgive you; but if you do not forgive others, neither will your Father forgive your trespasses. - Matthew 6:14-15 (NRSV)
In today’s Gospel Jesus teaches us how to pray to God.
The important thing that caught me about the Lord’s prayer, given that Jesus emphasises it again, was the concept of forgiveness.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-02-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-02-22/</guid><description>[1 Peter 5:1-4; Psalms 23:1-6; Matthew 16:13-19]
He said to them, “But who do you say that I am?” Simon Peter answered, “You are the Messiah, the Son of the living God.” And Jesus answered him, “Blessed are you, Simon son of Jonah! For flesh and blood has not revealed this to you, but my Father in heaven. And I tell you, you are Peter, and on this rock I will build my church, and the gates of Hades will not prevail against it.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-02-09/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-02-09/</guid><description>[Genesis 1:20–2:4; Psalms 8:4-9; Mark 7:1-13]
Then he said to them, “You have a fine way of rejecting the commandment of God in order to keep your tradition! For Moses said, ‘Honor your father and your mother’; and, ‘Whoever speaks evil of father or mother must surely die.’ But you say that if anyone tells father or mother, ‘Whatever support you might have had from me is Corban’ (that is, an offering to God)— then you no longer permit doing anything for a father or mother, thus making void the word of God through your tradition that you have handed on.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-02-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-02-08/</guid><description>[Genesis 1:1-19; Psalms 104:1-2, 5-6, 10, 12, 24, 35; Mark 6:53-56]
And wherever he went, into villages or cities or farms, they laid the sick in the marketplaces, and begged him that they might touch even the fringe of his cloak; and all who touched it were healed. - Mark 6:56 (NRSV)
In today’s Gospel, we read about how people thronged to even touch Jesus’ cloak, and that mere act was enough for them to be healed.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-28/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-28/</guid><description>[Hebrews 10:19-25; Psalms 24:1-6; Mark 4:21-25]
He said to them, “Is a lamp brought in to be put under the bushel basket, or under the bed, and not on the lampstand? For there is nothing hidden, except to be disclosed; nor is anything secret, except to come to light. Let anyone with ears to hear listen!” - Mark 4:21-23 (NRSV)
In today’s Gospel, Jesus speaks about shining the light in us, and not hiding it.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-27/</guid><description>[Hebrews 10:11-18; Psalms 110:1-4; Mark 4:1-20]
“Listen! A sower went out to sow. And as he sowed, some seed fell on the path, and the birds came and ate it up. Other seed fell on rocky ground, where it did not have much soil, and it sprang up quickly, since it had no depth of soil. And when the sun rose, it was scorched; and since it had no root, it withered away.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-25/</guid><description>[Acts 22:3-16; Psalms 117:1-2; Mark 16:15-18]
“While I was on my way and approaching Damascus, about noon a great light from heaven suddenly shone about me. I fell to the ground and heard a voice saying to me, ‘Saul, Saul, why are you persecuting me?’ I answered, ‘Who are you, Lord?’ Then he said to me, ‘I am Jesus of Nazareth whom you are persecuting.’ Now those who were with me saw the light but did not hear the voice of the one who was speaking to me.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-21/</guid><description>[Hebrews 7:25–8:6; Psalms 40:7-10, 17; Mark 3:7-12]
Whenever the unclean spirits saw him, they fell down before him and shouted, “You are the Son of God!” But he sternly ordered them not to make him known. - Mark 3:11-12 (NRSV)
I was quite struck by these verses. When evil spirits saw Jesus, they fell before him shouting that He is the Son of God. They saw Him and were scared of Him.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-20/</guid><description>[Hebrews 7:1-3, 15-17; Psalms 110:1-4; Mark 3:1-6]
“Is it lawful to do good or to do harm on the sabbath, to save life or to kill?” But they were silent. He looked around at them with anger; he was grieved at their hardness of heart and said to the man, “Stretch out your hand.” He stretched it out, and his hand was restored. - Mark 3:4b-5 (NRSV)
In today’s Gospel, we read about Jesus healing a man with a withered hand on the Sabbath.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-12/</guid><description>[Hebrews 2:5-12; Psalms 8:2, 5-9; Mark 1:21-28]
Just then there was in their synagogue a man with an unclean spirit, and he cried out, “What have you to do with us, Jesus of Nazareth? Have you come to destroy us? I know who you are, the Holy One of God.” But Jesus rebuked him, saying, “Be silent, and come out of him!” And the unclean spirit, convulsing him and crying with a loud voice, came out of him.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-08/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-08/</guid><description>[1 John 5:5-13; Psalms 147:12-15, 19-20; Luke 5:12-16]
If we receive human testimony, the testimony of God is greater; for this is the testimony of God that he has testified to his Son. Those who believe in the Son of God have the testimony in their hearts. Those who do not believe in God have made him a liar by not believing in the testimony that God has given concerning his Son.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-06/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-06/</guid><description>[1 John 4:11-18; Psalms 72:1-2, 10, 12-13; Mark 6:45-52] Immediately he made his disciples get into the boat and go on ahead to the other side, to Bethsaida, while he dismissed the crowd. After saying farewell to them, he went up on the mountain to pray. When evening came, the boat was out on the sea, and he was alone on the land. - Mark 6:45-47 (NRSV) In today&amp;rsquo;s Gospel, we read about Jesus walking on water.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2021-01-04/</guid><description>[1 John 3:2~4:6; Psalms 2:7bc-8, 10-12a; Matthew 4:12-17, 23-25]
and we receive from him whatever we ask, because we obey his commandments and do what pleases him. And this is his commandment, that we should believe in the name of his Son Jesus Christ and love one another, just as he has commanded us. All who obey his commandments abide in him, and he abides in them. And by this we know that he abides in us, by the Spirit that he has given us.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-31/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-31/</guid><description>[1 John 2:18-21; Psalms 96:1-2, 11-13; John 1:1-18]
In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. He was in the beginning with God. All things came into being through him, and without him not one thing came into being. What has come into being in him was life, and the life was the light of all people. The light shines in the darkness, and the darkness did not overcome it.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-23/</guid><description>[Malachi 3:1-4, 23-24; Psalms 25:4-5, 8-10, 14; LUKE 1:57-66]
On the eighth day they came to circumcise the child, and they were going to name him Zechariah after his father. But his mother said, “No; he is to be called John.” They said to her, “None of your relatives has this name.” Then they began motioning to his father to find out what name he wanted to give him. He asked for a writing tablet and wrote, “His name is John.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-21/</guid><description>[Song of Solomon 2:8-14; Psalms 33:2-3, 11-12, 20-21; Luke 1:39-45] And blessed is she who believed that there would be a fulfillment of what was spoken to her by the Lord. - Luke 1:39 (NRSV) In today&amp;rsquo;s reading, we read about Mary visiting Elizabeth.
The part about the Gospel that struck me was these words of Elizabeth where she calls Mary Blesses, for she believed that what was spoken to her would be fulfilled.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-16/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-16/</guid><description>[Isaiah 45:6-8, 18, 21-25; Psalms 85:9-14; Luke 7:18-23]
When the men had come to him, they said, “John the Baptist has sent us to you to ask, ‘Are you the one who is to come, or are we to wait for another?’” Jesus had just then cured many people of diseases, plagues, and evil spirits, and had given sight to many who were blind. And he answered them, “Go and tell John what you have seen and heard: the blind receive their sight, the lame walk, the lepers are cleansed, the deaf hear, the dead are raised, the poor have good news brought to them.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-14/</guid><description>[Numbers 24:2-7, 15-17; Psalms 25:4-9; Matthew 21:23-27]
Did the baptism of John come from heaven, or was it of human origin?” And they argued with one another, “If we say, ‘From heaven,’ he will say to us, ‘Why then did you not believe him?’ But if we say, ‘Of human origin,’ we are afraid of the crowd; for all regard John as a prophet.” So they answered Jesus, “We do not know.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-11/</guid><description>[Isaiah 48:17-19; Psalms 1:1-2, 3, 4, 6; Matthew 11:16-19]
For John came neither eating nor drinking, and they say, ‘He has a demon’; the Son of Man came eating and drinking, and they say, ‘Look, a glutton and a drunkard, a friend of tax collectors and sinners!’ Yet wisdom is vindicated by her deeds.” - Matthew 11:18-19 (NRSV)
In today’s Gospel, Jesus talks about accepting the Kingdom of God.
This Gospel reminds me of how fickle-minded the world we live in is.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-10/</guid><description>[Isaiah 41:13-20; Psalms 145:1, 9, 10-11, 12-13; Matthew 11:11-15]
Truly I tell you, among those born of women no one has arisen greater than John the Baptist; yet the least in the kingdom of heaven is greater than he. - Matthew 11:11 (NRSV)
In today’s Gospel Jesus talks about the least in the Kingdom of Heaven being greater than John the Baptist.
Jesus says that there was no one born who was greater than John the Baptist, this would imply that John the Baptist was one of the greatest Prophets, and there was no one greater than him.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-09/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-09/</guid><description>[Isaiah 40:25-31; Psalms 103:1-2, 3-4, 8, 10; Matthew 11:28-30]
“Come to me, all you that are weary and are carrying heavy burdens, and I will give you rest. Take my yoke upon you, and learn from me; for I am gentle and humble in heart, and you will find rest for your souls. For my yoke is easy, and my burden is light.” - Matthew 11:28-30 (NRSV)
Today’s Gospel is a reminder for us when we feel burdened by all our problems.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-07/</guid><description>[Isaiah 35:1-10; Psalms 85:9-10, 11-12, 13-14; Luke 5:17-26]
When he saw their faith, he said, “Friend, your sins are forgiven you.” Then the scribes and the Pharisees began to question, “Who is this who is speaking blasphemies? Who can forgive sins but God alone?” When Jesus perceived their questionings, he answered them, “Why do you raise such questions in your hearts? Which is easier, to say, ‘Your sins are forgiven you,’ or to say, ‘Stand up and walk’?</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-04/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-04/</guid><description>[Isaiah 29:17-24; Psalms 27:1, 4, 13-14; Matthew 9:27-31]
and Jesus said to them, “Do you believe that I am able to do this?” They said to him, “Yes, Lord.” Then he touched their eyes and said, “According to your faith let it be done to you.” And their eyes were opened. - Matthew 9:28-30a (NRSV)
In today’s Gospel, we read about Jesus healing the blind men.
An interesting thing that caught my attention was that Jesus only asks them, If they believe He can do this, and He then says “According to your faith let it be done to you.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-03/</guid><description>[Isaiah 26:1-6; Psalms 118:1, 8-9, 19-21, 25-27; Matthew 7:21, 24-27]
“Not everyone who says to me, ‘Lord, Lord,’ will enter the kingdom of heaven, but only the one who does the will of my Father in heaven. - Matthew 7:21 (NRSV)
In today’s Gospel Jesus speaks about doing the will of the Father
God our Father has a specific will for every one of us. It’s our life&amp;rsquo;s purpose to seek Him, to Know Him and discern His will for us in our lives.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-02/</guid><description>[Isaiah 25:6-10; Psalms 23:1-6; Matthew 15:29-37]
Then Jesus called his disciples to him and said, “I have compassion for the crowd, because they have been with me now for three days and have nothing to eat; and I do not want to send them away hungry, for they might faint on the way.” The disciples said to him, “Where are we to get enough bread in the desert to feed so great a crowd?</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-01/</guid><description>[Isaiah 11:1-10; Psalms 72:1, 7-8, 12-13, 17; Luke 10:21-24]
At that same hour Jesus rejoiced in the Holy Spirit and said, “I thank you, Father, Lord of heaven and earth, because you have hidden these things from the wise and the intelligent and have revealed them to infants; yes, Father, for such was your gracious will. All things have been handed over to me by my Father; and no one knows who the Son is except the Father, or who the Father is except the Son and anyone to whom the Son chooses to reveal him.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-30/</guid><description>[Romans 10:9-18; Psalms 19:2-3, 4-5; Matthew 4:18-22]
“The scripture says, “No one who believes in him will be put to shame.” For there is no distinction between Jew and Greek; the same Lord is Lord of all and is generous to all who call on him. For, “Everyone who calls on the name of the Lord shall be saved.” But how are they to call on one in whom they have not believed?</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-26/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-26/</guid><description>[Revelation 18:1-2, 21-23; 19:1-3, 9; Psalms 100:2, 3, 4, 5; Luke 21:20-28]
“There will be signs in the sun, the moon, and the stars, and on the earth distress among nations confused by the roaring of the sea and the waves. People will faint from fear and foreboding of what is coming upon the world, for the powers of the heavens will be shaken. Then they will see ‘the Son of Man coming in a cloud’ with power and great glory.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-25/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-25/</guid><description>[Revelation 15:1-4; Psalms 98:1-3, 7-9; Luke 21:12-19]
“But before all this occurs, they will arrest you and persecute you; they will hand you over to synagogues and prisons, and you will be brought before kings and governors because of my name. This will give you an opportunity to testify. So make up your minds not to prepare your defense in advance; for I will give you words and a wisdom that none of your opponents will be able to withstand or contradict.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-24/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-24/</guid><description>[Revelation 14:14-19; Psalms 96:10-13; Luke 21:5-11]
They asked him, “Teacher, when will this be, and what will be the sign that this is about to take place?” And he said, “Beware that you are not led astray; for many will come in my name and say, ‘I am he!’ and, ‘The time is near!’ Do not go after them.
“When you hear of wars and insurrections, do not be terrified; for these things must take place first, but the end will not follow immediately.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-23/</guid><description>[Revelation 14:1-5; Psalms 24:1-6; Luke 21:1-4]
He looked up and saw rich people putting their gifts into the treasury; he also saw a poor widow put in two small copper coins. He said, “Truly I tell you, this poor widow has put in more than all of them; for all of them have contributed out of their abundance, but she out of her poverty has put in all she had to live on.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-20/</guid><description>[Revelation 10:8-11; Psalms 119:14, 24, 72, 103, 111, 131; Luke 19:45-48]
Then he entered the temple and began to drive out those who were selling things there; and he said, “It is written,‘My house shall be a house of prayer’; but you have made it a den of robbers.” - Luke 19:45-46 (NRSVCE)
This is the second time we read of Jesus clearing the temple.
This verse reminds me again about the sanctity of our bodies.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-19/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-19/</guid><description>[Revelation 5:1-10; Psalms 149:1-6, 9; Luke 19:41-44]
Then I saw in the right hand of the one seated on the throne a scroll written on the inside and on the back, sealed with seven seals; and I saw a mighty angel proclaiming with a loud voice, “Who is worthy to open the scroll and break its seals?” And no one in heaven or on earth or under the earth was able to open the scroll or to look into it.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-18/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-18/</guid><description>[Revelation 4:1-11; Psalms 150:1-2, 3-4, 5-6; Luke 19:11-28]
‘I tell you, to all those who have, more will be given; but from those who have nothing, even what they have will be taken away. But as for these enemies of mine who did not want me to be king over them—bring them here and slaughter them in my presence.’” - Luke 19:26-27 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we read about the Parable of the Ten Pounds.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-17/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-17/</guid><description>[Revelation 3:1-6, 14-22; Psalms 15:2-3, 3-4, 5; Luke 19:1-10]
“Zacchaeus, hurry and come down; for I must stay at your house today.” So he hurried down and was happy to welcome him… …Then Jesus said to him, “Today salvation has come to this house, because he too is a son of Abraham. For the Son of Man came to seek out and to save the lost.” - Luke 19:5b-6,9-10 (NRSVCE)</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-16/</guid><description>[Revelation 1:1-4; 2:1-5; Psalms 1:1-4, 6; Luke 18:35-43]
“What do you want me to do for you?” He said, “Lord, let me see again.” Jesus said to him, “Receive your sight; your faith has saved you.” Immediately he regained his sight and followed him, glorifying God; and all the people, when they saw it, praised God. - Luke 18:41-43 (NRSVCE)
Today&amp;rsquo;s Gospel is quite interesting. We see a blind man regain his sight.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-13/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-13/</guid><description>[2 John 4-9; Psalms 119:1-2, 10-11, 17-18; Luke 17:26-37]
Just as it was in the days of Noah, so too it will be in the days of the Son of Man. They were eating and drinking, and marrying and being given in marriage, until the day Noah entered the ark, and the flood came and destroyed all of them. Likewise, just as it was in the days of Lot: they were eating and drinking, buying and selling, planting and building, but on the day that Lot left Sodom, it rained fire and sulfur from heaven and destroyed all of them —it will be like that on the day that the Son of Man is revealed.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-12/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-12/</guid><description>[Philemon 7-20; Psalms 146:7-10; Luke 17:20-25]
Being asked by the Pharisees when the kingdom of God was coming, he answered them, &amp;ldquo;The kingdom of God is not coming with signs to be observed; nor will they say, Lo, here it is!' or There!' for behold, the kingdom of God is in the midst of you.&amp;rdquo; - Luke 17:20-21 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we hear Jesus speak more about the Kingdom as well as His death and resurrection.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-11/</guid><description>[Titus 3:1-7; Psalms 23:1-6; Luke 17:11-19]
Then Jesus asked, “Were not ten made clean? But the other nine, where are they? Was none of them found to return and give praise to God except this foreigner?” - Luke 17:17-18 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we read about the ten lepers who were cleaned. They all came to Jesus and called out to Him to have mercy on them. Jesus tells them to go and show themselves to the priests, and as they were doing as He told them to, they were cleaned.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-10/</guid><description>[Titus 2:1-8, 11-14; Psalms 37:3-4, 18, 23, 27, 29; Luke 17:7-10]
So you also, when you have done all that you were ordered to do, say, ‘We are worthless slaves; we have done only what we ought to have done!’” - Luke 17:10 (NRSVCE)
Today’s Gospel can sound a bit difficult to read at first glance. An important prelude to this is what comes in the previous verses, where the disciples ask Jesus, How to increase their faith?</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-09/</guid><description>[Ezekiel 47:1-2, 8-9, 12; Psalms 46:2-3, 5-6, 8-9; 1 Corinthians 3:9-11, 16-17; John 2:13-22]
Making a whip of cords, he drove all of them out of the temple, both the sheep and the cattle. He also poured out the coins of the money changers and overturned their tables. He told those who were selling the doves, “Take these things out of here! Stop making my Father’s house a marketplace!” - John 2:15-16 (NRSVCE)</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-06/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-06/</guid><description>[Philippians 3:17–4:1; Psalms 122:1-5; Luke 16:1-8]
And his master commended the dishonest manager because he had acted shrewdly; for the children of this age are more shrewd in dealing with their own generation than are the children of light. - Luke 16:8 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we read about the dishonest steward. A steward is someone who has been appointed on behalf of another - a monarch, a rich man, etc.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-05/</guid><description>[Wisdom of Solomon 3:1-9; Psalms 23:1-6; John 6:37-40]
“But the souls of the righteous are in the hand of God, and no torment will ever touch them. In the eyes of the foolish they seemed to have died, and their departure was thought to be a disaster, and their going from us to be their destruction; but they are at peace.” - Wisdom 3:1-3 (NRSV-CI)
In today’s reading, we hear once again about death and eternity.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-04/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-04/</guid><description>[Philippians 2:12-18; Psalms 27:1, 4, 13-14; Luke 14:25-33]
“Whoever comes to me and does not hate father and mother, wife and children, brothers and sisters, yes, and even life itself, cannot be my disciple. Whoever does not carry the cross and follow me cannot be my disciple. - Luke 14:26-27 (NRSVCE)
Today’s Gospel sounds a rather radical statement by Christ. When we read it at first glance, it comes off as odd, and we might wonder what is Jesus asking of us!</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-03/</guid><description>[Philippians 2:5-11; Psalms 22:26-32; Luke 14:15-24]
Then the master said to the slave, ‘Go out into the roads and lanes, and compel people to come in, so that my house may be filled. For I tell you, none of those who were invited will taste my dinner.’” - Luke 14:23-24 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we read The Parable of the Great Dinner. The gist of the story is that a man once hosted a great dinner and invited many.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-02/</guid><description>[Wisdom 3:1-9; Psalms 27:1, 4, 7-9, 13-14; Romans 5:5-11; John 11:17-27]
Jesus said to her, “I am the resurrection and the life. Those who believe in me, even though they die, will live, and everyone who lives and believes in me will never die. Do you believe this?” - John 11:25-27 (NRSVCE)
Today the church celebrates All Souls Day, and we are called to pray for our near and dear ones who passed away from this Earth.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-30/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-30/</guid><description>[Philippians 1:1-11; Psalms 111:1-6; Luke 14:1-6]
And this is my prayer, that your love may overflow more and more with knowledge and full insight to help you to determine what is best, so that in the day of Christ you may be pure and blameless, having produced the harvest of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ for the glory and praise of God. - Philippians 1:9-11 (NRSVCE)
Today&amp;rsquo;s First Reading is the salutation from the Letter of St.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-29/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-29/</guid><description>[Ephesians 6:10-20; Psalms 144:1-2, 9-10; Luke 13:31-35]
Finally, be strong in the Lord and in the strength of his power. Put on the whole armor of God, so that you may be able to stand against the wiles of the devil. For our struggle is not against enemies of blood and flesh, but against the rulers, against the authorities, against the cosmic powers of this present darkness, against the spiritual forces of evil in the heavenly places.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-28/</guid><description>[Ephesians 2:19-22; Psalms 19:2-5; Luke 6:12-16]
So then you are no longer strangers and aliens, but you are citizens with the saints and also members of the household of God, built upon the foundation of the apostles and prophets, with Christ Jesus himself as the cornerstone. In him the whole structure is joined together and grows into a holy temple in the Lord; in whom you also are built together spiritually into a dwelling place for God.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-27/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-27/</guid><description>[Ephesians 5:21-33; Psalms 128:1-5; Luke 13:18-21]
He said therefore, “What is the kingdom of God like? And to what should I compare it? It is like a mustard seed that someone took and sowed in the garden; it grew and became a tree, and the birds of the air made nests in its branches.” And again he said, “To what should I compare the kingdom of God? It is like yeast that a woman took and mixed in with three measures of flour until all of it was leavened.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-26/</guid><description>[Ephesians 4:32–5:8; Psalms 1:1-4, 6; Luke 13:10-17]
“You hypocrites! Does not each of you on the sabbath untie his ox or his donkey from the manger, and lead it away to give it water? And ought not this woman, a daughter of Abraham whom Satan bound for eighteen long years, be set free from this bondage on the sabbath day?” - Luke 13:15b-16 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we hear of Jesus healing a crippled woman.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-22/</guid><description>[Ephesians 3:14-21; Psalms 33:1-2, 4-5, 11-12, 18-19; Luke 12:49-53]
From now on five in one household will be divided, three against two and two against three; they will be divided: father against son and son against father, mother against daughter and daughter against mother, mother-in-law against her daughter-in-law and daughter-in-law against mother-in-law.” - Luke 12:52-53 (NRSVCE)
Today’s Gospel reading seems very harsh and when read at face value makes you wonder what Jesus is telling us.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-21/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-21/</guid><description>[Ephesians 2:12-22; Psalms 85:9-14; Luke 12:35-38]
“Be dressed for action and have your lamps lit; be like those who are waiting for their master to return from the wedding banquet, so that they may open the door for him as soon as he comes and knocks. Blessed are those slaves whom the master finds alert when he comes; truly I tell you, he will fasten his belt and have them sit down to eat, and he will come and serve them.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-20/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-20/</guid><description>[Ephesians 2:12-22; Psalms 85:9-14; Luke 12:35-38]
So then you are no longer strangers and aliens, but you are citizens with the saints and also members of the household of God, built upon the foundation of the apostles and prophets, with Christ Jesus himself as the cornerstone. In him the whole structure is joined together and grows into a holy temple in the Lord; in whom you also are built together spiritually into a dwelling place for God.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-19/</guid><description>[Ephesians 2:1-10; Psalms 100:2-5; Luke 12:13-21]
You were dead through the trespasses and sins in which you once lived, following the course of this world, following the ruler of the power of the air, the spirit that is now at work among those who are disobedient…. …For by grace you have been saved through faith, and this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God— not the result of works, so that no one may boast.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-29/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-29/</guid><description>[Daniel 7:9-10, 13-14; Psalms 138:1-5; John 1:47-51]
Nathanael asked him, “Where did you get to know me?” Jesus answered, “I saw you under the fig tree before Philip called you.” - John 1:48 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we see Jesus calling Philip and Nathaniel. IF you read a few verses before this, you’ll find that Jesus had called Philip, and Philip then called Nathaniel. When Nathaniel meets Jesus, He welcomes him and tells him that He saw him under the fig tree before Philip called him.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-25/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-25/</guid><description>[Ecclesiastes 3:1-11; Psalms 144:1-4; Luke 9:18-22]
For everything there is a season, and a time for every matter under heaven:
a time to be born, and a time to die;
a time to plant, and a time to pluck up what is planted; - Ecclesiastes 3:1-2 (NRSVCE)
Today’s First Reading is one of my favourite verses in the Bible. I love the poetry in it, and the truth and deep meaning in it.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-17/</guid><description>[Galatians 6:14-18; Galatians 2:16, 20; Philippians 1:20-21; Luke 9:23-26]
Then he said to them all, “If any want to become my followers, let them deny themselves and take up their cross daily and follow me. For those who want to save their life will lose it, and those who lose their life for my sake will save it. What does it profit them if they gain the whole world, but lose or forfeit themselves?</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-16/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-16/</guid><description>[1 Corinthians 12:31&amp;ndash;13:13; Psalms 33:2-5, 12, 22; Luke 7:31-35]
Love is patient; love is kind; love is not envious or boastful or arrogant or rude. It does not insist on its own way; it is not irritable or resentful; it does not rejoice in wrongdoing, but rejoices in the truth. It bears all things, believes all things, hopes all things, endures all things. 1 Corinthians 13:4-7 (NRSVCE)
Today’s First reading is one of my all-time favourite readings in the Bible.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-15/</guid><description>[Hebrews 5:7-9; Psalms 31:2-6,15-16,20; John 19:25-27]
“When Jesus saw his mother and the disciple whom he loved standing beside her, he said to his mother, “Woman, here is your son.” Then he said to the disciple, “Here is your mother.” And from that hour the disciple took her into his own home.” - John 19:26-27 (NRSV-CI)
In today’s Gospel we read about the final minutes of Jesus as a human being in this Earth.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-10/</guid><description>In today’s Gospel, Jesus talks to us about loving our enemies
“But I say to you that listen, Love your enemies, do good to those who hate you, bless those who curse you, pray for those who abuse you.” - Luke 6:27-28 (NRSV-CI)
The two most important commandments that Jesus called out was to love your Lord and God with all your heart and the next commandment was to love your neighbour as yourself.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-09/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-09/</guid><description>In today’s Gospel we hear Jesus speak out what we called the Beattitudes. He says
“Blessed are you who are poor, for yours is the kingdom of God. Blessed are you who are hungry now, for you will be filled. Blessed are you who weep now, for you will laugh.” - Luke 6:20b-21 (NRSV-CI)
We all live on this earth and we’re like pilgrims here. This is not our final destination.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-01/</guid><description>[1 Corinthians 2:10-18; Psalms 145:8-14; Luke 4:31-37]
For what human being knows what is truly human except the human spirit that is within? So also no one comprehends what is truly God’s except the Spirit of God. Now we have received not the spirit of the world, but the Spirit that is from God, so that we may understand the gifts bestowed on us by God. And we speak of these things in words not taught by human wisdom but taught by the Spirit, interpreting spiritual things to those who are spiritual.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-31/</guid><description>[1 Corinthians 2:1-5; Psalms 119:97-102; Luke 4:16-30]
My speech and my proclamation were not with plausible words of wisdom, but with a demonstration of the Spirit and of power, so that your faith might rest not on human wisdom but on the power of God. - 1 Corinthians 2:4-5 (NRSVCE)
In today’s First Reading, Paul makes a very striking statement. He states that he spoke to them purely in line with what the Holy Spirit directed him to.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-26/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-26/</guid><description>[2 Thessalonians 3:6-10, 16-18; Psalms 128:1-2, 4-5; Matthew 23:27-32]
Now we command you, brethren, in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ, that you keep away from any brother who is living in idleness and not in accord with the tradition that you received from us. For you yourselves know how you ought to imitate us; we were not idle when we were with you, we did not eat any one’s bread without paying, but with toil and labor we worked night and day, that we might not burden any of you.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-24/</guid><description>[Revelation 21:9-14; Psalms 145:10-13, 17-18; John 1:45-51]
Nathanael asked him, “Where did you get to know me?” Jesus answered, “I saw you under the fig tree before Philip called you.” Nathanael replied, “Rabbi, you are the Son of God! You are the King of Israel!” Jesus answered, “Do you believe because I told you that I saw you under the fig tree? You will see greater things than these.” John 1:48-50</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-21/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-21/</guid><description>[Ezekiel 37:1-14; Psalms 107:2-9; Matthew 22:34-40]
He said to him, “‘You shall love the Lord your God with all your heart, and with all your soul, and with all your mind.’ This is the greatest and first commandment. And a second is like it: ‘You shall love your neighbor as yourself.’ On these two commandments hang all the law and the prophets.” - Matthew 22:37-40 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel Jesus tells us what are the most important commandments to follow.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-20/</guid><description>[Ezekiel 36:23-28; Psalms 51:12-15, 18-19; Matthew 22:1-14]
“But when the king came in to see the guests, he noticed a man there who was not wearing a wedding robe, and he said to him, ‘Friend, how did you get in here without a wedding robe?’ And he was speechless. Then the king said to the attendants, ‘Bind him hand and foot, and throw him into the outer darkness, where there will be weeping and gnashing of teeth.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-18/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-18/</guid><description>[Ezekiel 28:1-10; Deuteronomy 32:26-28, 30, 35-36; Matthew 19:23-30]
And everyone who has left houses or brothers or sisters or father or mother or children or fields, for my name’s sake, will receive a hundredfold, and will inherit eternal life. But many who are first will be last, and the last will be first. - Matthew 19:29-30 (NRSVCE)
Today’s Gospel continues from yesterday’s with the story of the rich man. The part that struck me most about today’s Gospel was how Jesus explains the importance of keeping our eyes set on eternity.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-17/</guid><description>[Ezekiel 24:15-23; Deuteronomy 32:18-21; Matthew 19:16-22]
The young man said to him, “I have kept all these; what do I still lack?” Jesus said to him, “If you wish to be perfect, go, sell your possessions, and give the money to the poor, and you will have treasure in heaven; then come, follow me.” - Matthew 19:20-21 (NRSVCE)
Today’s Gospel is very striking. A rich young man comes to Jesus and asks Him what must He do to have eternal life.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-14/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-14/</guid><description>[1 John 3:13-18; Psalms 116:10-13, 16-17; John 15:12-17]
“This is my commandment, that you love one another as I have loved you. No one has greater love than this, to lay down one’s life for one’s friends. You are my friends if you do what I command you. I do not call you servants any longer, because the servant does not know what the master is doing; but I have called you friends, because I have made known to you everything that I have heard from my Father.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-13/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-13/</guid><description>[Ezekiel 12:1-2; Psalms 78:56-59, 61-62; Matthew 18:21-19:1]
Then Peter came and said to him, “Lord, if another member of the church sins against me, how often should I forgive? As many as seven times?” Jesus said to him, “Not seven times, but, I tell you, seventy-seven times. - Matthew 18:21-22 (NRSVCE)
Today’s Gospel speaks about forgiveness. Jesus uses the parable of the unforgiving servant to teach us about the justice of God.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-12/</guid><description>[Ezekiel 9:1-7; 10:18-22; Psalms 113:1-6; Matthew 18:15-20]
“If another member of the church sins against you, go and point out the fault when the two of you are alone. If the member listens to you, you have regained that one. But if you are not listened to, take one or two others along with you, so that every word may be confirmed by the evidence of two or three witnesses. If the member refuses to listen to them, tell it to the church; and if the offender refuses to listen even to the church, let such a one be to you as a Gentile and a tax collector.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-11/</guid><description>[Ezekiel 2:8 - 3:4; Psalms 119:14, 24, 72, 103, 111, 131; Matthew 18:1-5, 10, 12-14]
Truly I tell you, unless you change and become like children, you will never enter the kingdom of heaven. Whoever becomes humble like this child is the greatest in the kingdom of heaven. Whoever welcomes one such child in my name welcomes me. - Matthew 18:3-5 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we see the disciples asking Jesus - Who is the greatest in the kingdom of heaven?</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-10/</guid><description>[2 Corinthians 9:6-10; Psalms 112:1-2, 5-9; John 12:24-26]
Very truly, I tell you, unless a grain of wheat falls into the earth and dies, it remains just a single grain; but if it dies, it bears much fruit. Those who love their life lose it, and those who hate their life in this world will keep it for eternal life. Whoever serves me must follow me, and where I am, there will my servant be also.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-05/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-05/</guid><description>[Jeremiah 31:1-7; Jeremiah 31:10-13; Matthew 15:21-28]
He answered, “I was sent only to the lost sheep of the house of Israel.” But she came and knelt before him, saying, “Lord, help me.” He answered, “It is not fair to take the children’s food and throw it to the dogs.” She said, “Yes, Lord, yet even the dogs eat the crumbs that fall from their masters’ table.” Then Jesus answered her, “Woman, great is your faith!</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-04/</guid><description>[Jeremiah 30:1-2, 12-15, 18-22; Psalms 102:16-21, 29, 22-23; Matthew 14:22-36]
Peter answered him, “Lord, if it is you, command me to come to you on the water.” He said, “Come.” So Peter got out of the boat, started walking on the water, and came toward Jesus. But when he noticed the strong wind, he became frightened, and beginning to sink, he cried out, “Lord, save me!” Jesus immediately reached out his hand and caught him, saying to him, “You of little faith, why did you doubt?</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-03/</guid><description>[Jeremiah 28:1-17; Psalms 119:29, 43, 79, 80, 95, 102; Matthew 14:22-36]
but by this time the boat, battered by the waves, was far from the land, for the wind was against them. And early in the morning he came walking toward them on the sea. But when the disciples saw him walking on the sea, they were terrified, saying, “It is a ghost!” And they cried out in fear. - Matthew 14:24-26 (NRSVCE)</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-31/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-31/</guid><description>[Jeremiah 26:1-9; Psalms 69:5, 8-10, 14; Matthew 13:54-58]
But Jesus said to them, “Prophets are not without honor except in their own country and in their own house.” And he did not do many deeds of power there, because of their unbelief. - Matthew 13:57b-58 (NRSVCE)
In Today’s Gospel, we see Jesus going back to His hometown, the place where he was raised, that familiar place where most people knew Him.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-30/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-30/</guid><description>Can I not do with you, O house of Israel, just as this potter has done? says the Lord. Just like the clay in the potter’s hand, so are you in my hand, O house of Israel. Jeremiah 18:6 (NRSVCE)
The part about the today’s Liturgy that struck me ware these words from God to Jeremiah. God is the Potter and we are the clay. We might have melded ourselves into an indistingusihable shape, but God wants to shape us into something new and wonderful.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-29/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-29/</guid><description>[Jeremiah 15:10, 16-21; Psalms 59:2-4, 10-11, 17-18; John 11:19-27]
Jesus said to her, “I am the resurrection and the life. Those who believe in me, even though they die, will live, and everyone who lives and believes in me will never die. Do you believe this?” - John 11:25-26 (NRSVCE)
IN Today’s Gospel we see Jesus raise Lazarus from the dead. The words above were spoken by Jesus when Martha tells Jesus that he could saved her brother, had He come earlier.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-28/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-28/</guid><description>[Jeremiah 14:17-22; Psalms 79:8-9, 11, 13; Matthew 13:36-43]
“The one who sows the good seed is the Son of Man; the field is the world, and the good seed are the children of the kingdom; the weeds are the children of the evil one, and the enemy who sowed them is the devil; the harvest is the end of the age, and the reapers are angels. - Matthew 13:37b-39 (NRSVCE)</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-27/</guid><description>[Jeremiah 13:1-11; Deuteronomy 32:18-21; Matthew 13:31-35]
He put before them another parable: “The kingdom of heaven is like a mustard seed that someone took and sowed in his field; it is the smallest of all the seeds, but when it has grown it is the greatest of shrubs and becomes a tree, so that the birds of the air come and make nests in its branches.” - Matthew 13:31-32 (NRSVCE)</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-24/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-24/</guid><description>[Jeremiah 3:14-17; Jeremiah 31:10-13; Matthew 13:18-23]
But as for what was sown on good soil, this is the one who hears the word and understands it, who indeed bears fruit and yields, in one case a hundredfold, in another sixty, and in another thirty. - Matthew 13:23 (NRSVCE)
In Today’s Gospel Jesus explains to His disciples the Parable of the Sower. The Parable of the Sower very clearly explains to us, how we ought to receive the Word of God.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-23/</guid><description>[Jeremiah 2:1-3, 7-8, 12-13; Psalms 36:6-11; Matthew 13:10-17]
The reason I speak to them in parables is that ‘seeing they do not perceive, and hearing they do not listen, nor do they understand.’ With them indeed is fulfilled the prophecy of Isaiah that says: ‘You will indeed listen, but never understand, and you will indeed look, but never perceive. - Matthew 12:13-15 (NRSVCE)
Today’s Gospel passage is a very interesting one.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-22/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-22/</guid><description>[2 Corinthians 5:14-17; Psalms 63:2-6, 8-9; John 20:1-2, 11-18]
Jesus said to her, “Woman, why are you weeping? Whom are you looking for?” Supposing him to be the gardener, she said to him, “Sir, if you have carried him away, tell me where you have laid him, and I will take him away.” Jesus said to her, “Mary!” She turned and said to him in Hebrew, “Rabbouni!” (which means Teacher). - John 20:15-16 (NRSVCE)</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-21/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-21/</guid><description>[Micah 7:14-15, 18-20; Psalms 85:2-4, 5-6, 7-8; Matthew12:46-50]
Who is a God like you, pardoning iniquity and passing over the transgression of the remnant of your possession? He does not retain his anger forever, because he delights in showing clemency. - Micah 7:18 (NRSVCE)
Today’s First Reading gives us another reminder of God’s mercy. Despite all the atrcoties and sins of the people of Israel, God will show mercy, and cast all our sins to the sea, says Micah.</description></item><item><title>Daily Reflection</title><link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-07-20/</guid><description>[Micah 6:1-4, 6-8; Psalms 50:5-6, 8-9, 16-17, 21, 23; Matthew 12:38-42]
He has told you, O mortal, what is good; and what does the Lord require of you but to do justice, and to love kindness, and to walk humbly with your God? - Micah 6:8 (NRSVCE)
Today’s First Reading touches again on the theme of what God truly wants of us. We see this being echoed in the readings of the past few days.</description></item></channel></rss>