<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Daily Reflections by Mario Stallone</title>
    <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Daily Reflections by Mario Stallone</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-03/</guid>
      <description>[Isaiah 26:1-6; Psalms 118:1, 8-9, 19-21, 25-27; Matthew 7:21, 24-27]
“Not everyone who says to me, ‘Lord, Lord,’ will enter the kingdom of heaven, but only the one who does the will of my Father in heaven. - Matthew 7:21 (NRSV)
In today’s Gospel Jesus speaks about doing the will of the Father
God our Father has a specific will for every one of us. It’s our life&amp;rsquo;s purpose to seek Him, to Know Him and discern His will for us in our lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-02/</guid>
      <description>[Isaiah 25:6-10; Psalms 23:1-6; Matthew 15:29-37]
Then Jesus called his disciples to him and said, “I have compassion for the crowd, because they have been with me now for three days and have nothing to eat; and I do not want to send them away hungry, for they might faint on the way.” The disciples said to him, “Where are we to get enough bread in the desert to feed so great a crowd?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-12-01/</guid>
      <description>[Isaiah 11:1-10; Psalms 72:1, 7-8, 12-13, 17; Luke 10:21-24]
At that same hour Jesus rejoiced in the Holy Spirit and said, “I thank you, Father, Lord of heaven and earth, because you have hidden these things from the wise and the intelligent and have revealed them to infants; yes, Father, for such was your gracious will. All things have been handed over to me by my Father; and no one knows who the Son is except the Father, or who the Father is except the Son and anyone to whom the Son chooses to reveal him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-30/</guid>
      <description>[Romans 10:9-18; Psalms 19:2-3, 4-5; Matthew 4:18-22]
“The scripture says, “No one who believes in him will be put to shame.” For there is no distinction between Jew and Greek; the same Lord is Lord of all and is generous to all who call on him. For, “Everyone who calls on the name of the Lord shall be saved.” But how are they to call on one in whom they have not believed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-26/</guid>
      <description>[Revelation 18:1-2, 21-23; 19:1-3, 9; Psalms 100:2, 3, 4, 5; Luke 21:20-28]
“There will be signs in the sun, the moon, and the stars, and on the earth distress among nations confused by the roaring of the sea and the waves. People will faint from fear and foreboding of what is coming upon the world, for the powers of the heavens will be shaken. Then they will see ‘the Son of Man coming in a cloud’ with power and great glory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-25/</guid>
      <description>[Revelation 15:1-4; Psalms 98:1-3, 7-9; Luke 21:12-19]
“But before all this occurs, they will arrest you and persecute you; they will hand you over to synagogues and prisons, and you will be brought before kings and governors because of my name. This will give you an opportunity to testify. So make up your minds not to prepare your defense in advance; for I will give you words and a wisdom that none of your opponents will be able to withstand or contradict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-24/</guid>
      <description>[Revelation 14:14-19; Psalms 96:10-13; Luke 21:5-11]
They asked him, “Teacher, when will this be, and what will be the sign that this is about to take place?” And he said, “Beware that you are not led astray; for many will come in my name and say, ‘I am he!’ and, ‘The time is near!’ Do not go after them.
“When you hear of wars and insurrections, do not be terrified; for these things must take place first, but the end will not follow immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-23/</guid>
      <description>[Revelation 14:1-5; Psalms 24:1-6; Luke 21:1-4]
He looked up and saw rich people putting their gifts into the treasury; he also saw a poor widow put in two small copper coins. He said, “Truly I tell you, this poor widow has put in more than all of them; for all of them have contributed out of their abundance, but she out of her poverty has put in all she had to live on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-20/</guid>
      <description>[Revelation 10:8-11; Psalms 119:14, 24, 72, 103, 111, 131; Luke 19:45-48]
Then he entered the temple and began to drive out those who were selling things there; and he said, “It is written,‘My house shall be a house of prayer’; but you have made it a den of robbers.” - Luke 19:45-46 (NRSVCE)
This is the second time we read of Jesus clearing the temple.
This verse reminds me again about the sanctity of our bodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-19/</guid>
      <description>[Revelation 5:1-10; Psalms 149:1-6, 9; Luke 19:41-44]
Then I saw in the right hand of the one seated on the throne a scroll written on the inside and on the back, sealed with seven seals; and I saw a mighty angel proclaiming with a loud voice, “Who is worthy to open the scroll and break its seals?” And no one in heaven or on earth or under the earth was able to open the scroll or to look into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-18/</guid>
      <description>[Revelation 4:1-11; Psalms 150:1-2, 3-4, 5-6; Luke 19:11-28]
‘I tell you, to all those who have, more will be given; but from those who have nothing, even what they have will be taken away. But as for these enemies of mine who did not want me to be king over them—bring them here and slaughter them in my presence.’” - Luke 19:26-27 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we read about the Parable of the Ten Pounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-17/</guid>
      <description>[Revelation 3:1-6, 14-22; Psalms 15:2-3, 3-4, 5; Luke 19:1-10]
“Zacchaeus, hurry and come down; for I must stay at your house today.” So he hurried down and was happy to welcome him… …Then Jesus said to him, “Today salvation has come to this house, because he too is a son of Abraham. For the Son of Man came to seek out and to save the lost.” - Luke 19:5b-6,9-10 (NRSVCE)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-16/</guid>
      <description>[Revelation 1:1-4; 2:1-5; Psalms 1:1-4, 6; Luke 18:35-43]
“What do you want me to do for you?” He said, “Lord, let me see again.” Jesus said to him, “Receive your sight; your faith has saved you.” Immediately he regained his sight and followed him, glorifying God; and all the people, when they saw it, praised God. - Luke 18:41-43 (NRSVCE)
Today&amp;rsquo;s Gospel is quite interesting. We see a blind man regain his sight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-13/</guid>
      <description>[2 John 4-9; Psalms 119:1-2, 10-11, 17-18; Luke 17:26-37]
Just as it was in the days of Noah, so too it will be in the days of the Son of Man. They were eating and drinking, and marrying and being given in marriage, until the day Noah entered the ark, and the flood came and destroyed all of them. Likewise, just as it was in the days of Lot: they were eating and drinking, buying and selling, planting and building, but on the day that Lot left Sodom, it rained fire and sulfur from heaven and destroyed all of them —it will be like that on the day that the Son of Man is revealed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-12/</guid>
      <description>[Philemon 7-20; Psalms 146:7-10; Luke 17:20-25]
Being asked by the Pharisees when the kingdom of God was coming, he answered them, &amp;ldquo;The kingdom of God is not coming with signs to be observed; nor will they say, Lo, here it is!&#39; or There!&#39; for behold, the kingdom of God is in the midst of you.&amp;rdquo; - Luke 17:20-21 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we hear Jesus speak more about the Kingdom as well as His death and resurrection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-11/</guid>
      <description>[Titus 3:1-7; Psalms 23:1-6; Luke 17:11-19]
Then Jesus asked, “Were not ten made clean? But the other nine, where are they? Was none of them found to return and give praise to God except this foreigner?” - Luke 17:17-18 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we read about the ten lepers who were cleaned. They all came to Jesus and called out to Him to have mercy on them. Jesus tells them to go and show themselves to the priests, and as they were doing as He told them to, they were cleaned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-10/</guid>
      <description>[Titus 2:1-8, 11-14; Psalms 37:3-4, 18, 23, 27, 29; Luke 17:7-10]
So you also, when you have done all that you were ordered to do, say, ‘We are worthless slaves; we have done only what we ought to have done!’” - Luke 17:10 (NRSVCE)
Today’s Gospel can sound a bit difficult to read at first glance. An important prelude to this is what comes in the previous verses, where the disciples ask Jesus, How to increase their faith?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-09/</guid>
      <description>[Ezekiel 47:1-2, 8-9, 12; Psalms 46:2-3, 5-6, 8-9; 1 Corinthians 3:9-11, 16-17; John 2:13-22]
Making a whip of cords, he drove all of them out of the temple, both the sheep and the cattle. He also poured out the coins of the money changers and overturned their tables. He told those who were selling the doves, “Take these things out of here! Stop making my Father’s house a marketplace!” - John 2:15-16 (NRSVCE)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-06/</guid>
      <description>[Philippians 3:17–4:1; Psalms 122:1-5; Luke 16:1-8]
And his master commended the dishonest manager because he had acted shrewdly; for the children of this age are more shrewd in dealing with their own generation than are the children of light. - Luke 16:8 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we read about the dishonest steward. A steward is someone who has been appointed on behalf of another - a monarch, a rich man, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-05/</guid>
      <description>[Wisdom of Solomon 3:1-9; Psalms 23:1-6; John 6:37-40]
“But the souls of the righteous are in the hand of God, and no torment will ever touch them. In the eyes of the foolish they seemed to have died, and their departure was thought to be a disaster, and their going from us to be their destruction; but they are at peace.” - Wisdom 3:1-3 (NRSV-CI)
In today’s reading, we hear once again about death and eternity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-04/</guid>
      <description>[Philippians 2:12-18; Psalms 27:1, 4, 13-14; Luke 14:25-33]
“Whoever comes to me and does not hate father and mother, wife and children, brothers and sisters, yes, and even life itself, cannot be my disciple. Whoever does not carry the cross and follow me cannot be my disciple. - Luke 14:26-27 (NRSVCE)
Today’s Gospel sounds a rather radical statement by Christ. When we read it at first glance, it comes off as odd, and we might wonder what is Jesus asking of us!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-03/</guid>
      <description>[Philippians 2:5-11; Psalms 22:26-32; Luke 14:15-24]
Then the master said to the slave, ‘Go out into the roads and lanes, and compel people to come in, so that my house may be filled. For I tell you, none of those who were invited will taste my dinner.’” - Luke 14:23-24 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we read The Parable of the Great Dinner. The gist of the story is that a man once hosted a great dinner and invited many.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-11-02/</guid>
      <description>[Wisdom 3:1-9; Psalms 27:1, 4, 7-9, 13-14; Romans 5:5-11; John 11:17-27]
Jesus said to her, “I am the resurrection and the life. Those who believe in me, even though they die, will live, and everyone who lives and believes in me will never die. Do you believe this?” - John 11:25-27 (NRSVCE)
Today the church celebrates All Souls Day, and we are called to pray for our near and dear ones who passed away from this Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-30/</guid>
      <description>[Philippians 1:1-11; Psalms 111:1-6; Luke 14:1-6]
And this is my prayer, that your love may overflow more and more with knowledge and full insight to help you to determine what is best, so that in the day of Christ you may be pure and blameless, having produced the harvest of righteousness that comes through Jesus Christ for the glory and praise of God. - Philippians 1:9-11 (NRSVCE)
Today&amp;rsquo;s First Reading is the salutation from the Letter of St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-29/</guid>
      <description>[Ephesians 6:10-20; Psalms 144:1-2, 9-10; Luke 13:31-35]
Finally, be strong in the Lord and in the strength of his power. Put on the whole armor of God, so that you may be able to stand against the wiles of the devil. For our struggle is not against enemies of blood and flesh, but against the rulers, against the authorities, against the cosmic powers of this present darkness, against the spiritual forces of evil in the heavenly places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-28/</guid>
      <description>[Ephesians 2:19-22; Psalms 19:2-5; Luke 6:12-16]
So then you are no longer strangers and aliens, but you are citizens with the saints and also members of the household of God, built upon the foundation of the apostles and prophets, with Christ Jesus himself as the cornerstone. In him the whole structure is joined together and grows into a holy temple in the Lord; in whom you also are built together spiritually into a dwelling place for God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-27/</guid>
      <description>[Ephesians 5:21-33; Psalms 128:1-5; Luke 13:18-21]
He said therefore, “What is the kingdom of God like? And to what should I compare it? It is like a mustard seed that someone took and sowed in the garden; it grew and became a tree, and the birds of the air made nests in its branches.” And again he said, “To what should I compare the kingdom of God? It is like yeast that a woman took and mixed in with three measures of flour until all of it was leavened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-26/</guid>
      <description>[Ephesians 4:32–5:8; Psalms 1:1-4, 6; Luke 13:10-17]
“You hypocrites! Does not each of you on the sabbath untie his ox or his donkey from the manger, and lead it away to give it water? And ought not this woman, a daughter of Abraham whom Satan bound for eighteen long years, be set free from this bondage on the sabbath day?” - Luke 13:15b-16 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we hear of Jesus healing a crippled woman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-22/</guid>
      <description>[Ephesians 3:14-21; Psalms 33:1-2, 4-5, 11-12, 18-19; Luke 12:49-53]
From now on five in one household will be divided, three against two and two against three; they will be divided: father against son and son against father, mother against daughter and daughter against mother, mother-in-law against her daughter-in-law and daughter-in-law against mother-in-law.” - Luke 12:52-53 (NRSVCE)
Today’s Gospel reading seems very harsh and when read at face value makes you wonder what Jesus is telling us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-21/</guid>
      <description>[Ephesians 2:12-22; Psalms 85:9-14; Luke 12:35-38]
“Be dressed for action and have your lamps lit; be like those who are waiting for their master to return from the wedding banquet, so that they may open the door for him as soon as he comes and knocks. Blessed are those slaves whom the master finds alert when he comes; truly I tell you, he will fasten his belt and have them sit down to eat, and he will come and serve them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-20/</guid>
      <description>[Ephesians 2:12-22; Psalms 85:9-14; Luke 12:35-38]
So then you are no longer strangers and aliens, but you are citizens with the saints and also members of the household of God, built upon the foundation of the apostles and prophets, with Christ Jesus himself as the cornerstone. In him the whole structure is joined together and grows into a holy temple in the Lord; in whom you also are built together spiritually into a dwelling place for God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-10-19/</guid>
      <description>[Ephesians 2:1-10; Psalms 100:2-5; Luke 12:13-21]
You were dead through the trespasses and sins in which you once lived, following the course of this world, following the ruler of the power of the air, the spirit that is now at work among those who are disobedient…. …For by grace you have been saved through faith, and this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God— not the result of works, so that no one may boast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-29/</guid>
      <description>[Daniel 7:9-10, 13-14; Psalms 138:1-5; John 1:47-51]
Nathanael asked him, “Where did you get to know me?” Jesus answered, “I saw you under the fig tree before Philip called you.” - John 1:48 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel, we see Jesus calling Philip and Nathaniel. IF you read a few verses before this, you’ll find that Jesus had called Philip, and Philip then called Nathaniel. When Nathaniel meets Jesus, He welcomes him and tells him that He saw him under the fig tree before Philip called him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-25/</guid>
      <description>[Ecclesiastes 3:1-11; Psalms 144:1-4; Luke 9:18-22]
For everything there is a season, and a time for every matter under heaven:
a time to be born, and a time to die;
a time to plant, and a time to pluck up what is planted; - Ecclesiastes 3:1-2 (NRSVCE)
Today’s First Reading is one of my favourite verses in the Bible. I love the poetry in it, and the truth and deep meaning in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-17/</guid>
      <description>[Galatians 6:14-18; Galatians 2:16, 20; Philippians 1:20-21; Luke 9:23-26]
Then he said to them all, “If any want to become my followers, let them deny themselves and take up their cross daily and follow me. For those who want to save their life will lose it, and those who lose their life for my sake will save it. What does it profit them if they gain the whole world, but lose or forfeit themselves?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-16/</guid>
      <description>[1 Corinthians 12:31&amp;ndash;13:13; Psalms 33:2-5, 12, 22; Luke 7:31-35]
Love is patient; love is kind; love is not envious or boastful or arrogant or rude. It does not insist on its own way; it is not irritable or resentful; it does not rejoice in wrongdoing, but rejoices in the truth. It bears all things, believes all things, hopes all things, endures all things. 1 Corinthians 13:4-7 (NRSVCE)
Today’s First reading is one of my all-time favourite readings in the Bible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-15/</guid>
      <description>[Hebrews 5:7-9; Psalms 31:2-6,15-16,20; John 19:25-27]
“When Jesus saw his mother and the disciple whom he loved standing beside her, he said to his mother, “Woman, here is your son.” Then he said to the disciple, “Here is your mother.” And from that hour the disciple took her into his own home.” - John 19:26-27 (NRSV-CI)
In today’s Gospel we read about the final minutes of Jesus as a human being in this Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-10/</guid>
      <description>In today’s Gospel, Jesus talks to us about loving our enemies
“But I say to you that listen, Love your enemies, do good to those who hate you, bless those who curse you, pray for those who abuse you.” - Luke 6:27-28 (NRSV-CI)
The two most important commandments that Jesus called out was to love your Lord and God with all your heart and the next commandment was to love your neighbour as yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-09/</guid>
      <description>In today’s Gospel we hear Jesus speak out what we called the Beattitudes. He says
“Blessed are you who are poor, for yours is the kingdom of God. Blessed are you who are hungry now, for you will be filled. Blessed are you who weep now, for you will laugh.” - Luke 6:20b-21 (NRSV-CI)
We all live on this earth and we’re like pilgrims here. This is not our final destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-09-01/</guid>
      <description>[1 Corinthians 2:10-18; Psalms 145:8-14; Luke 4:31-37]
For what human being knows what is truly human except the human spirit that is within? So also no one comprehends what is truly God’s except the Spirit of God. Now we have received not the spirit of the world, but the Spirit that is from God, so that we may understand the gifts bestowed on us by God. And we speak of these things in words not taught by human wisdom but taught by the Spirit, interpreting spiritual things to those who are spiritual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-31/</guid>
      <description>[1 Corinthians 2:1-5; Psalms 119:97-102; Luke 4:16-30]
My speech and my proclamation were not with plausible words of wisdom, but with a demonstration of the Spirit and of power, so that your faith might rest not on human wisdom but on the power of God. - 1 Corinthians 2:4-5 (NRSVCE)
In today’s First Reading, Paul makes a very striking statement. He states that he spoke to them purely in line with what the Holy Spirit directed him to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-26/</guid>
      <description>[2 Thessalonians 3:6-10, 16-18; Psalms 128:1-2, 4-5; Matthew 23:27-32]
Now we command you, brethren, in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ, that you keep away from any brother who is living in idleness and not in accord with the tradition that you received from us. For you yourselves know how you ought to imitate us; we were not idle when we were with you, we did not eat any one’s bread without paying, but with toil and labor we worked night and day, that we might not burden any of you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-24/</guid>
      <description>[Revelation 21:9-14; Psalms 145:10-13, 17-18; John 1:45-51]
Nathanael asked him, “Where did you get to know me?” Jesus answered, “I saw you under the fig tree before Philip called you.” Nathanael replied, “Rabbi, you are the Son of God! You are the King of Israel!” Jesus answered, “Do you believe because I told you that I saw you under the fig tree? You will see greater things than these.” John 1:48-50</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-21/</guid>
      <description>[Ezekiel 37:1-14; Psalms 107:2-9; Matthew 22:34-40]
He said to him, “‘You shall love the Lord your God with all your heart, and with all your soul, and with all your mind.’ This is the greatest and first commandment. And a second is like it: ‘You shall love your neighbor as yourself.’ On these two commandments hang all the law and the prophets.” - Matthew 22:37-40 (NRSVCE)
In today’s Gospel Jesus tells us what are the most important commandments to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-20/</guid>
      <description>[Ezekiel 36:23-28; Psalms 51:12-15, 18-19; Matthew 22:1-14]
“But when the king came in to see the guests, he noticed a man there who was not wearing a wedding robe, and he said to him, ‘Friend, how did you get in here without a wedding robe?’ And he was speechless. Then the king said to the attendants, ‘Bind him hand and foot, and throw him into the outer darkness, where there will be weeping and gnashing of teeth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Reflection</title>
      <link>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariostallone.com/reflections/posts/2020-08-18/</guid>
      <description>[Ezekiel 28:1-10; Deuteronomy 32:26-28, 30, 35-36; Matthew 19:23-30]
And everyone who has left houses or brothers or sisters or father or mother or children or fields, for my name’s sake, will receive a hundredfold, and will inherit eternal life. But many who are first will be last, and the last will be first. - Matthew 19:29-30 (NRSVCE)
Today’s Gospel continues from yesterday’s with the story of the rich man. The part that struck me most about today’s Gospel was how Jesus explains the importance of keeping our eyes set on eternity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
